Thomas Clarke

See my LinkedIn for more contact information – linkedin.com/in/tombclarke

Profile:

A degree in Computer Science is allowing me to explore my interests and fuel my passion for technology. I am task focused, have a positive attitude and an industrious work ethic, all of which are important for my degree and for the real world of work. I have worked in several different working environments, all of which are giving me new experiences to help build myself and prepare me for my future. I can adapt to new environments quickly and deal with problems effectively.

Qualifications:

Currently studying: University of Birmingham - BSc in Computer Science with a Year in Industry - September 2014 to July 2018

- 2nd Year Modules: Databases and Online Programming, Functional Programming (in Haskell), Professional Computing, Mathematical Techniques for Computer Science, Computational Vision, Modules of Computation, Team Project, Computer Systems and Architecture, C/C++ and Computer Security
- 1st Year Results Year average was 85%: Robotics (100%), Software Engineering (78%), Software Workshop Java (95%), Language and Logic (85%), Web Programming (88%), Foundations of Computer Science (with functional programming in OCaml) (82%), Artificial Intelligence (77%), Information Engineering (73%) and Multimedia Data (70%)

John Cleveland College - September 2010 to August 2014

- A Levels: Mathematics (A*), Physics (A), I.C.T. (A), AS History (C), Extended Project Qualification (A).
- GCSEs: 3 A*s, 6 As, 1 B and OCR Level 2 National Double Award in I.C.T. (Distinction).

Technical Skills:

- I can program in Java (experienced with the Eclipse IDE), C# (used in Unity), MATLAB, OCaml, Haskell, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (including jQuery and D3.js), PHP and SQL.
- Experience with designing and creating experimental data visualisations (see labs.majestic.com).
- Function programming experience.
- Programming robots using LeJOS and scoring 100% in this module.
- Good experience with version control system Git.
- Basic knowledge of Android Development and Visual Basic.

Work History:

- Web Developer, Hinckley Homeless group, September 2015, Voluntary: I created a new website for Hinckley Homeless Group to replace their original one using an agile approach to development.
- Software Developer, Majestic, July to September 2015: Using various web technologies and utilising D3.js, me and a team of 2 other developers are using the Majestic API to create data visualisations. The work can be seen at https://labs.majestic.com. I also represented Majestic at Leeds Hack 2015.
- Supervisor (promoted from sales assistant March 2015), Spar, October 2014 to present: Responsibilities include supervising sales assistants, operating the shop, handling money, maintaining important systems and more of the shop in general and handling more customer queries.

Thomas Clarke

See my LinkedIn for more contact information – linkedin.com/in/tombclarke

- Software Tester, Crane Electronics Ltd., Summer 2014: Responsibilities involved exploring and testing a range of products to identify faults or problems and reporting them to the software engineer for revision. The main project was black box testing on an Android based device.
- Garden Centre Assistant, Woodlands Nursery & Garden Centre, October 2013 to January 2014: Responsibilities involved fast-paced customer service and till working.
- IT Department, Aston Martin, Warwick, July 2011: Responsibilities involved building new computers for the assembly line and installing them across the factory.

Achievements and Interests

- Attending various hackathons:
 - I represented Majestic at Leeds Hack 2015 (leedshack.org) as a sponsor, where I gave
 a short introductory presentation on Majestic, and worked with the attendees on
 using the Majestic API in their projects.
 - BrumHack 2.0 where our team created a fast-paced fighting game in Unity using C# and having to create extra C# programs to run within the game to gather information about various websites using Majestic's API.
- Taking part in UoB Games Development Society's Game Jams.
- Tutored in GCSE Computing and A-Level Mathematics.
- I have participated in extra circular activities including:
 - o an EPQ (Extended Project Qualification) based on creating an Android Application,
 - o a Silver Crest Award based on Astronomy,
 - o a v50 volunteering award,
- Member of the Computer Science Society and Games Development Society.
- Bass guitar (achieved Merit at Grade 3).
- Socialising, live music, game design and travelling.

References:

- University of Birmingham Computer Science:
 - Hamid Dehghani
 - o Tel: +44 (0)121 414 8728
 - o Email: H.Dehghani@cs.bham.ac.uk
- Majestic-12 Ltd:
 - Steve Pitchford
 - o Email: stevep@majesticseo.com